COLIN LEWIS

+46 73-033 89 04

HELLO@COLINLEWIS.SE
HTTPS://COLINLEWIS.SE
GITHUB.COM/UNLIKELYOBJECTS

PROFILE

I am a designer, front end developer, and writer. I have over a decade of experience working with WordPress development and web design, and I'm passionate about solving problems and understanding user needs.

VÄSTRA PRINSGATAN 16A 371 35 KARLSKRONA SWEDEN

SKILLS

Hard skills:

Adobe CS (Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop), Balsamic, Hype, Invision, Sketch.

HTML5, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, WordPress, Git, Bootstrap, responsive design, WCAG 2.0.

Soft skills:

Project and team management, concept development, prototyping, storytelling, creative problem solving.

I have extensive training in creating high-functioning teams, Susan Wheelan's effective team concepts, and the Co-Active leadership model.

EXPERIENCE

Expert Developer, Codeable; Remote · 2019-present

Codeable is an exclusive freelancer platform that connects businesses with premium WordPress developers.

Owner, Unlikely Objects AB; Karlskrona, SWE · 2017-present

Unlikely Objects is a storytelling studio that produces digital experiences, unusual books, and games that combine literature, film, interactivity and delight. It is also my Hyper Island thesis project founded with assistance from and in cooperation with Blekinge Business Incubator.

Web designer & developer, Freelance \cdot 2013-present

Web design and front end development, WordPress, strategy, web app UI design, branding.

My responsibilities as freelance web designer span nearly the entire range of a web project: ideation, strategy and design, custom WordPress theme development, and client education.

Communicator, Tierps Municipality; Tierp, SWE · 2012-2013

Public information officer – PR and communications strategy in the Tierp Municipality Department of Culture.

As Communicator I was responsible for investigating and serving the needs of all the Culture Department sections, including Children & Youth, Athletics, and the municipal library. I created graphic profiles for these individual offices and employed them in a series of advertising campaigns. The new branding resulted in an immediate increase of public engagement at the municipality's cultural and athletic events.

Web designer & developer, Freelance · 2010-2012

Web design and front end development, WordPress. End to end project creation, supervision, development and delivery.

Consultant, Tierps Municipality; Tierp, SWE · 1997-2012

I organised and promoted the annual art festival *Konst på väg* in Tierps municipality together with the head of the Culture Department and a small team. I worked with marketing, strategy, and above all as designer and developer in the creation of promotional material: the festival's website and the printed catalogue. During my tenure, participation in the event increased over 500%.

Web designer, Fingerpaint; Saratoga Springs, NY, USA · 2009-2010

Web design, front end development, web app UI and email marketing design, ExpressionEngine, WordPress.

I completed a team of five designers and developers that produced sites for local and national businesses.

Web designer & developer, Freelance · 2002-2009

Web design and front end development, WordPress, ExpressionEngine. I first worked with WordPress in 2004.

EDUCATION

Hyper Island, Karlskrona, SWE · YH, 2015-2017

Digital Media Creative is a program that allows students to develop their design, technological, management and entrepreneurial skills. I attended the learning hub in Karlskrona, Sweden.

University of Gävle, Gävle, SWE · 2005-2007

Creative writing in English.

LANGUAGES

English & Swedish.